focusgroup.com 2019-11-05

# Privacy Policy

Last Modified 8/19/2019

**PRIVACY  POLICY AND RESPONDENT BILL OF RIGHTS**  

We would like to take this opportunity to thank you for visiting our website/mobile application and/or downloading our App. We appreciate that visitors may be concerned about privacy. For this reason, we have developed the following Privacy Policy and Respondent Bill of Rights. If you have questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please direct questions to [yourprivacy@focuspointeglobal.com](mailto:yourprivacy@focuspointeglobal.com?subject=A%20question%20about%20your%20privacy%20policy)

**HOW WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION**  
We maintain administrative, technical and physical safeguards in an effort to protect against unauthorized disclosure, use, alteration or destruction of any personal information you may provide to this website/mobile application.

**HOW WE COLLECT AND USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION AND WHY WE COLLECT IT**  
We collect certain information when you visit our website/mobile application. This information tells us such things as how many people visit our site/mobile application and which pages they have visited. This information assists us with maintaining and designing a user-friendly website/mobile application.

We collect this information through “browser cookies” (as described below). To assist visitors with technical problems, we also may collect local web configuration information, including browser type, operating system, and various other browser settings.

In addition, our web servers automatically collect limited information about your computer/phone when you visit our website/mobile application. This information may include the type of browser software you use, the operating system you’re running, the IP address assigned to your computer or Internet connection, and the IP address of the website/mobile application, if any, that referred you to our website/mobile application. Our technical staff may also use this information to assist customers with technical problems.

If you decide to sign up with us for the purpose of participating in our research studies, we will collect information about you that will enable us to determine whether you qualify for one or more research studies, and that will enable us to invite you to participate in those specific studies. You may be contacted via email, through our mobile app (FPG POV), and/or by telephone.

**BROWSER COOKIES**  
FPG uses browser cookies to enhance your online experience. Browser cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer/phone’s hard drive when you visit certain website/mobile applications. We utilize browser cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited our website/mobile application before or if you’re a new visitor. Browser cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular site. We also sometimes contract with third party companies who specialize in search engine optimization (SEO) and measurement services. Third parties may use browser cookies to collect or receive information from our website/mobile application and elsewhere on the internet and use that information to provide measurement services and target participation opportunities. If you wish to find out more about the use of cookies please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices). If you wish to stop receiving browser cookies from us, please contact us so that we may suggest ways for you to disable existing browser cookies. Please note that disabling browser cookies may prevent you from taking full advantage of all of our website/mobile application features.

**CONFIDENTIALITY / EXCEPTIONS**  
We do not knowingly reveal any personal information that is provided by our visitors or research study participants to any third parties except as provided in this Privacy Policy, when requested to do so by a governmental agency having jurisdiction, by a court of competent jurisdiction or other operation of law, or when we believe that disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We reserve the right to securely transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use the personal information you have provided through this website/mobile application in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy. 

**QUESTIONNAIRES AND SURVEYS**  
Upon entering our website/mobile application, you may be asked to complete an online survey or questionnaire. These surveys and questionnaires will seek your opinions, attitudes, interests and even your activities online. Any personal information gathered through your participation in questionnaires or surveys will not be kept unless you agree to provide us with that information.

If you sign up to participate in our research studies, your personal information will only be used to determine your eligibility for a particular study, so that we can send you e-mails containing links to surveys or questionnaires to be completed online. There are times when we will contact you by telephone to determine your eligibility for a study without sending you an email invitation containing a screener link. Your name or contact information is never shared with the entity that requested we conduct the research. Personal information gathered through your participation in online surveys or questionnaires is not kept unless you agree to provide that information to us by filling out the Personal Profile section of our website/mobile application.  Profile information is used only to determine your eligibility for research studies and is kept strictly confidential.

**CHILDREN USING THE INTERNET**  
This website/mobile application is not intended for children under the age of 14. For that reason, we strongly encourage parents to supervise their children when visiting our website/mobile application. We do not collect personal information from children under the age of 14 unless we have parental consent. If you believe we have collected personal information from children under the age of 14, please notify us immediately so that we may take steps to eliminate such information. Participation in any research study for a child under the age of 18 will require parental consent.

**A WARNING ABOUT E-MAIL THAT WE SEND; A WARNING ABOUT “PHISHING”**  
We do not and will not at any time request any personal information via e-mail, nor will we include a link to an account login page in any e-mail. If you receive an e-mail requesting any personal information, including without limitation your social security number, your credit card or bank information, PLEASE DO NOT RESPOND BY PROVIDING ANY OF THE INFORMATION REQUESTED. We never request any of this information from you, even if you elect to sign up to participate in our research studies. If you receive an e-mail requesting any of this information, it is likely that you have received an attempted theft of your identity commonly called “phishing.” Likewise, if you receive an e-mail urging you to login to your account and providing you with a link to the login page, it is also likely that you have received a “phishing” e-mail. In either case, you should bring the e-mail to our attention by forwarding the e-mail to [yourprivacy@focuspointeglobal.com](mailto:yourprivacy@focuspointeglobal.com?subject=A%20question%20about%20your%20privacy%20policy). For more information about “phishing,” you should visit the Federal Trade Commission’s website/mobile application at www.ftc.gov.

**EFFECTIVE DATE OF THE PRIVACY POLICY; CHANGES**  
This Privacy Policy became effective September 8, 2011. The latest update to this policy took place on August 19, 2019.

We reserve the right to alter or amend this Privacy Policy at any time and without prior notice to you in order to reflect changes in our online information practices. In an effort to ensure that you receive notice of any changes to the Privacy Policy, we may include a notice on our website/mobile application. Alternatively, we may send a notice to the e-mail address you provide to us. If you have not provided us with an e-mail address, we will not be able to provide you with such notice. We also recommend that you check back with this web page periodically so that you may be kept informed regarding any changes to the Privacy Policy. You should also visit our Terms of Use in addition to this Privacy Policy.

**THIRD PARTY LINKS**  
Our website/mobile application may contain links to third party website/mobile applications that are not subject to this Privacy Policy. If you visit these website/mobile applications, we encourage you to read their privacy policies before providing them with any personal information.

**STATE LAW  **  
You may have privacy rights under applicable state law in addition to those outlined in this privacy policy.

**CONTACT US**  
If you choose to e-mail us through the “Contact Us” link on this website/mobile application, you will be asked to provide information such as your name and e-mail address so that one of our employees can respond to your questions and comments. If, however, you wish to submit your questions or comments via U.S. mail, they can be mailed to: 

Focus Pointe Global  
Attn:  Charlotte Daley  
100 Penn Square East, Suite 1200  
Philadelphia, PA 19107

**RESEARCH PARTICIPANT BILL OF RIGHTS**  
Your participation in public opinion survey research is very important to us, and we value the information you provide. We believe that all marketing research participants have certain rights, as follows:

  1. Your privacy and the privacy of your answers will be respected and maintained.
  2. Your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, personal information, and individual responses will not be disclosed to anyone outside the Focus Pointe Global network without your express permission.
  3. You will be informed in advance if an interview is to be recorded and of the intended use of the recording.
  4. Upon request, you will be informed of the privacy policy that applies to your participation in the research study.
  5. The researcher will be identified to you. You will be told the name of the research organization and the general nature of the survey.
  6. We will never sell you anything nor ask you for any money, under the guise of research or otherwise.
  7. We will endeavor to contact you at reasonable and convenient times. If, for any reason, the time is inconvenient, you may ask that we contact you again at a more convenient time.
  8. Your decision to participate in a study, answer specific questions, or discontinue your participation will be respected without question.
  9. We will endeavor to uphold the highest standards of professional conduct when collecting and reporting the information you provide.

Public Opinion research is an important part of our democratic society, allowing people to express their views on political and social issues. Your opinion counts!
